Soroush Jolai

soroushdevelope@gmail.com | +44 07402113436 | LinkedIn | London

Online Portfolio

PROFILE

As an experienced software engineer, I've been part of various tech industry teams, gaining valuable experience in web and games programming over the past four years. I graduated with a master's in Computer Games Technology with distinction. The focus of the course was mastering C++ programming and the math skills essential for crafting games. I've got a knack for picking up new programming languages quickly and working with others' code seamlessly.

EDUCATION

City, University of London, London, UK MSc Computer Games Technology

2023 - 2024

- Grade: **Distinction**. Advanced Games Technology, OOP in C++, Game Development Process, Computer Graphics, Games Architecture in C#, VR development.
- Dissertation: Developed a no-code game engine and editor in C# from scratch.

University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

BEng Electrical Engineering

2015 - 2019

- Grade: (2:1). Studied computer science basics, computer architecture, and programming in C.
- Learned various data structures and algorithms essential for software engineering.

KEY SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- Solid C# and C++ Programming skills.
- Solid Math and 3D physics knowledge.
- Experience in Shader programming (GLSL, OpenGL) and a good understanding of graphics pipelines.
- Experience with Unreal Engine, Unity, Engine Programming, Collision system, NPC behaviours.
- Familiarity with JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Python, and Git.

Languages: English (fluent), Persian (native), French (A2)

RECENT PROJECTS

Context: MonoEndlessRunner

Role: Designer and Developer

2/2024 - 7/2024

- Designed and developed a 3D game engine and editor using C# to create endless runner games.
- Implemented a GUI for game designers leveraging ImGui.Net.

Context: Monsterfall (Grade: 89/100)

Role: Developer

12/2023 - 2/2024

- Programmed a game and engine features in C# following the best practices.
- Implemented various programming design patterns (C#).
- Developed game engine features e.g. collision detection and response system.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

City, University of London, London, England

Engine Programmer

Sept. 2024 - Nov. 2024

- Updated build tools and libraries of the university's custom engine e.g. assimp loader.
- Implemented ray tracing feature in C++.
- Problem-solving: Fixed various issues e.g. faulty texture loading, bug in 3D skinned mesh model loader.
- Improved engine performance by reducing the initial loading time by 10%.

Tose'e Fanavari Arya Kavosh, Tehran, Iran

Software Developer

Oct. 2021 – Jun. 2022

- Programmed a professional website from scratch utilizing JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Vue.js/Nuxt.js also added some features to user panel e.g. a video player. Link to website
- Problem-solving: Troubleshot several issues in code structure and improved overall performance.
- Communication: Reported project progress to team lead and manager. Reported bugs in UI to design team.
- Teamwork: worked as part of a team of 6 people and efficiently communicated with colleagues from other backgrounds.